this is scond text from cmd
working tree
staging area
local repository ( commit means adding to local repository.)

syntax
git add __
>> this will add file to staging area

git commit -m ""
>> this shows the total changes in local repo like insertion, deletion and changed.

then change a file and do git commit

git log
>> it shows commit id "commit a9a6ae352ae9b5e4e4eb9628d946c62a891e6d17"
author, date, branch

create the remote repository and 
git remote add origin "--"

then see if there is connection
git config --list

push to the github
git push -u origin "master"

to see github branch
>>git branch
it will show which branch you are working.

create new branch
>> git branch new_one

to change branch 
>> git checkout name 
branch the change hunxa but pahila ko branch file haru arko new pani bancha, without st
branch the change hunxa but pahila ko branch file haru arko new pani bancha, without st
branch the change hunxa but pahila ko branch file haru arko new pani bancha, without stging we can't checkout

>> git checkout -b _name

to just switch
>> git switch name
just switch

to know about dir
>> dir

verifying the work of switch and checkout
>> git merge name

cloning
>> git clone _link
clone only give read acces 


pull or fork(fork can be done only from ui of github)



merge conflict
1st_branch and 2nd_branch both have one.txt with different content
now if i first merge 1st_branch in main, done
now again if i merge 2nd_branch to main branch then conflict arise.

To resolve
now user will have to give decisons which they want to put or not
