this is scond text from cmd
working tree
staging area
local repository ( commit means adding to local repository.)

syntax
git add __
>> this will add file to staging area

git commit -m ""
>> this shows the total changes in local repo like insertion, deletion and changed.

then change a file and do git commit

git log
>> it shows commit id "commit a9a6ae352ae9b5e4e4eb9628d946c62a891e6d17"
author, date, branch

create the remote repository and 
git remote add origin "--"

then see if there is connection
git config --list

push to the github
git push -u origin "master"